Speaker: Most people think that people who get up early do
better in life and get more done.
Many very successful and super-productive people get up between 4 and 6 a.m.,
for example: Tim Cook, Richard Branson, and Oprah Winfrey.
However, not all successful people are larks.
Famous night owls include Barack Obama, Charles Darwin, and Elvis Presley.
It’s a good idea to match your job to your type,
so owls are more suited to evening work or night shifts.
Let’s look at some other factors.
More women are larks.
More men are owls.
Teenagers of either sex are usually owls.
Older people are usually larks.
But actually, around 60% of people are a mix of the two types.
Type is also linked to personality.
Larks are normally more self-disciplined and orderly,
but owls are more extrovert and open.
So, the big question is…
Who is happier: the larks or the owls?
Well, studies have shown that…larks are happier!
Morning people are generally happier with life and have fewer mental health problems.
Owls are more at risk of depression.
But scientists think that it is possible to change your type.
If you want to become a lark, you can stop using digital devices in the evening,
practise going to bed earlier, and give yourself an early-morning reward,
for example, a delicious cup of coffee or some time on your iPad.
There’s good news for owls, though.
If you keep busy and motivated during the day,
it might be easier to go to sleep earlier at night.
So the next day, you can fly out of bed, happy as a lark!